《黑镜》
他们准备好了
They're ready now.
也许我们可以从去年五月那件事
Perhaps we could begin with your earliest recollections
你最早的回忆开始
of the events of last May.
好吧 我第一次被牵扯进去是15号
Well, I first got involved on the 15th.
你可以把麦克风挪近一点吗
Could you move the microphone a little closer?
这样吗
Here?
我第一次被牵扯进去是15号
I first got involved on the 15th.
《为国所恨》
(5月15日  第一天)
总理汤姆·皮克林捍卫着
Chancellor Tom Pickering has defended
政府在残废抚恤金一事上的立场
the government's stance on disability benefits
与此同时 “轮椅殉道者”格温·马里布之死引发了公众强烈的愤慨
as outrage over the death of so-called "Wheelchair Martyr" Gwen Marbury grows.
超过两万民众签署了请愿书
More than 20,000 people have signed a petition
要求解雇新闻评论员乔·鲍尔斯
demanding the sacking of newspaper columnist Jo Powers
源于她此前撰写了一篇关于格温·马里布的争议性文章
following her controversial article about Gwen Marbury.
自然资源保护论者宣布又一物种
Conservationists have announced another extinction.
西伯利亚白鹤已灭绝
The Siberian crane has died out
由于空前的湿地栖息地减少
following an unprecedented reduction in its wetland habitat.
一种名为人工智能蜂的模拟昆虫无人机
And the honeybee-mimicking drone insects known as ADIs
已经被激活 准备迎接他们的第二个夏季
have been activated for their second summer.
希望你为自己感到羞耻
Hope you're ashamed of yourself.
- 贱人 - 这都是我的荣幸
- Bitch. - Pleasure's all mine.
(新提醒)
由·鲍尔斯?
Yo Powers?
乔·鲍尔斯
Jo Powers.
里面的东西 会爆炸吗
Whatever's in there, will it detonate?
这是面包店寄来给你的
That's from bakery. For you.
- 谢谢 - 谢谢
- Thank you. - Thank you.
嗨 亲爱的
Hello, darling!
真有创意 你的祝福者们
Creative, your well-wishers.
(死贱人)
别吃
Don't eat it.
这是个蛋糕 蛋糕就该被吃掉
It's a cake. That's its job.
我去洗个澡
I'm going to have a bath.
∮ 起航远行 ∮
∮ Sail away ∮
∮ 去远航 去远航 去远航 ∮
∮ Sail away, sail away, sail away ∮
∮ 从比绍 到帕劳 阿瓦隆外的海角 ∮
∮ From Bissau to Palau in the shade of Avalon ∮
∮ 从斐济 到泰里 和伊博尼的岛 ∮
∮ From Fiji to Tiree and the Isles of Ebony ∮
∮ 从秘鲁 到宿务 巴比伦人的旅途 ∮
∮ From Peru to Cebu, hear the power of Babylon ∮
∮ 从巴厘 到卡利 ∮
∮ From Bali to Cali ∮
(乔·鲍尔斯 = 人渣)
(你是在开玩笑吗 尊重点别人 祝你下半生都坐在轮椅上度过 乔·鲍尔斯)
(我看了格温的书 至少她还做了点什么 而不是到处攻击别人 不尊重别人)
(你就是彻头彻尾的垃圾  乔·鲍尔斯 你该觉得羞耻)
(你个毫无同情心的贱人)
(你有超过200条新提醒  其中96条提到你)
(问：该给恶心的东西起什么名字？ 答：乔·鲍尔斯)
(乔·鲍尔斯 你妈的)
啊
Ah!
(恶心的贱人)
(去死吧)
(贱人中的贱人)
格莱美奖获得者 说唱歌手塔斯克 仍在现场
Grammy-award-winning rapper Tusk is still with us.
那么 塔斯克 网络上有许多
Now, Tusk, there are loads of online videos
人们试图去模仿你的视频
of people trying to emulate you,
但这个是我们的最爱  请看
but this is our favourite. Take a look at this.
这个年轻人名叫亚伦·希恩  他今年九岁
It's a young chap called Aaron Sheen. He's nine years old.
真是个蠢孩子
That is one goofy-looking kid.
跳得不怎么样
Not a good dancer.
他才九岁 别这样  他跳得很好了
He's nine years old! Come on, he's a pretty good dancer.
这小杂种根本不会跳舞
That young motherfucker can't dance for shit.
说真的 他应该快点放弃了
He should probably just give up now, actually.
别因为我说了真话就恨我
Don't hate on me for keeping it real.
这傻狍子样的小杂种 根本不会跳舞
That's a goofy little motherfucker, and he can't dance for shit.
他是你的铁杆粉丝 塔斯克
He is a big fan, Tusk.
别恨我
Don't hate on your boy.
每个人都有刚开始的时候
Everybody's got to start somewhere.
刚开始的时候  我比他看上去好多了
Start somewhere? I looked better than that...
- 你是帕克督查员吗 - 不接受采访
- DCI Parke? - No press.
不 我不是媒体 呃 技术资料中心 布鲁·科尔森  我是你的搭档
No, I'm not press. Um... TDC Blue Colson. I’m your shadow.
我的搭档吗  他们说
My shadow? They said...
抱歉  请叫我卡琳
Sorry. Call me Karin.
- 你是不是说你的名字叫 - 布鲁
- Did you say your name was...? - Blue.
- B-l-u-e 布鲁 - 嗯 不是绰号
- B-l-u-e, Blue? - Yeah. It's not a nickname.
- 我爸爸喜欢这名字的发音 - 嗯哼
- My dad liked the sound of it. - Uh-huh.
- 你以前见过尸体吗 - 见过一些
- Seen a body before? - A couple.
- 在录像里见过 - 老大
- On video, I mean. - Boss?
这是布鲁  我的搭档
This is Blue. She's my shadow.
- 我是尼克·谢尔顿警长 - 发现了什么
- DS Nick Shelton. - What've we got?
- 乔·鲍里斯 - 是
- Jo Powers. - As in...
就是那个乔·鲍里斯
As in actual Jo Powers.
我看过她写的关于坐轮椅的女人的文章
Saw something she wrote the other day about the wheelchair woman.
骗点击的东西  把人们惹恼了
Clickbait piece. Pissed people off.
那篇文章太可怕了  我也签了
That article was fucking horrendous. Even I signed the petition.
要求解雇她的请愿书
To get her sacked.
来吧
Come on.
邻居听到了她的尖叫 叫来了警察
Neighbours heard her screaming and called it in.
挣扎得很厉害
Hell of a struggle.
还有其他人在家吗
Anyone else at home?
她的丈夫  胃部被深砍了一刀
Husband. Found slashed across the stomach.
- 她砍的吗 - 不知道
- By her? - Don't know.
他在昏迷中  我们将他送到圣哥伦比亚医院了
He was unconscious. They've taken him to St. Columbus.
(来看看  警察封锁了乔·鲍里斯房子的周围  他们不可能活捉她)
(有消息称警察在乔·鲍里斯住处  希望他们因为她的言论逮捕她)
她的推特提醒源源不断
Her mentions are still pouring in.
窗是锁好的
Restraining bolt's in place.
- 没有其他入口吗 - 没有  但外面一圈都有闭路电视
- No other points of entry? - No. But the outside's ringed with CCTV.
- 我们有监控的控制码吗 - 有
- We got the code for the cams? - Uh-huh.
好的 那么  检查录像  把蛋糕打包拿去毒物学测试
Okay, then. Check the recordings. Bag that, send it to Toxicology.
全套尸检 等她丈夫醒过来就询问他
Full autop for her, and we question the husband as soon as he wakes up.
走吧
Come on.
- 你认为是她丈夫做的吗 - 我还不能肯定
- You think it's the husband? - I'm keeping options open.
割喉 这很不寻常  谢谢 小伙子
Cutting the throat, that's unusual. Thanks, chaps.
- 但你认为是他做的 - 现在还什么都不知道
- But you do think he did it? - Don't know anything yet.
这种事常常是源于饮酒 嗑药 和家庭纠纷
These things are almost always either drink, drugs or domestic.
就这么回事
It is how it is.
- 你开车回家吗 - 我没有驾照  从没通过考试
- You driving home? - No licence. Never passed.
我在等无人驾驶变成主流
I'm sort of waiting for driverless to go mainstream.
- 上车吧 - 不 老实说 我坐地铁
- Get in. - No, honestly, I'll get the Tube.
- 上车 - 噢 好吧
- Get in. - Oh. Okay.
- 你在科技犯罪部门吗 - 数字取证  电脑上的黑暗事物
- So you were in Tech Crime? - Digital Forensics. Computer murk.
怎么了 你觉得无聊了吗
What happened, you get bored of it?
也不是  你会看见人们试图藏起的东西
Not exactly. You've seen what people tuck away on these.
阴谋 死亡名单 儿童色情电影  一点都不无聊
Schemes and kill lists, kiddy porn. It's not boring.
我年轻的时候 还没有电脑
I'm old enough to remember when they walked around with that stuff
人们只是想想这些事情而已
just tucked away in their heads.
没错  但现在他们忍不住要把这些和小伙伴分享
Right. But now they can't help butentrusting it to their little companions.
电脑 网络 这些东西吸收了我们的人格  它们知晓我们的一切
These things absorb who we are. They know everything about us.
如果觉得有趣 为什么要离开取证部门
If it's interesting, why leave Forensics?
兰诺克案
The Rannoch case.
- 伊恩·兰诺克吗 - 对 那个杀害儿童的
- Ian Rannoch? - The child killings, yeah.
是我破解了他的纪念文件夹
I was the one who cracked his souvenir folder.
- 你看到了那些照片 - 嗯
- So you saw those pictures? - Mm-hmm.
还有视频  全看到了
And the videos too. Saw them all.
当你看到那种东西 你会被改变的
You see something like that, it changes you.
你要么受到严重的打击 要么你会想
You either get defeated or you think...
你会想 “我靠  我得帮忙阻止这种事”
You think, "Fuck me! I've got to help stop that shit."
嗯
Yeah.
- 我是说 在现场的话 - 什么现场
- I mean, out here in the field... - What fucking field?
你知道的啊  在现实世界
You know what I mean. Out here in the real world,
你可以真正地阻止事情发生 对吧
you can genuinely prevent stuff, can't you?
你太年轻了
You are young.
也许是你老了
Maybe you're old?
说什么呢
Steady.
谢谢
Thanks.
- 明天见 - 好的老板
- See you tomorrow. - Yes, boss.
乔·鲍里斯死于她位于西伦敦的家中
Jo Powers has been found dead at her home in West London.
这位资深专栏作家 生前撰写的
The veteran columnist had been at the centre of controversy
关于残障权益运动者格温·马布里的文章 引发了巨大争议
over an article she'd written about disability rights activist Gwen Marbury.
警方正在调查死亡原因
The police have yet to confirm the cause...
那是第一层 第一个房间
It's just the first floor, first door on the...
- 这么早就开始工作了吗 - 我让尼克给我看闭路电视的录像
- Starting early? - I asked Nick to show me the CCTV.
- 是吗 - 嗯
- Oh, yeah? - Yeah.
没人进出  整晚屋里都只有乔和她的丈夫
No one came in or out. Just Jo and her husband all evening.
- 那个是什么 - 后面的露天庭院
- And that one there? - Rear patio.
- 看这样子 似乎是几个月前被破坏的 - 可能有人从那里进了屋
- Bust for months by the looks of it. - Someone could've come in through there.
那必须翻过围墙进出
They'd have to climb the fence, make it in and out,
而且知道那里的摄像机不在摄录
knowing the camera wasn't working,
但是 技术上来说 可能会发生
but yeah, could have happened. Technically.
好的 抱歉
Okay, sorry.
你很热心帮忙啊
You're keen to help.
- 是她来问我的 - 嗯哼
- She just asked! - Uh-huh.
(乔·鲍尔特)
(贱人 婊子)
(滚蛋 荡妇 死 杀)
(实话说  乔·鲍尔斯这婊子要是被杀了 我做梦都会笑醒)
(签署请愿书！ 立刻解雇)
(乔·鲍尔斯死于火灾)
(乔·鲍尔斯这荡妇该死)
呃 所以
Um... So...
我正在整理过去48小时内针对乔·鲍尔斯的
I'm collating every threat or insult levelled at Jo Powers
恐吓和侮辱言论
over the previous 48 hours.
假设真是他老公  那也太巧合了 不是么
Say it is the husband. That's a coincidence, isn't it?
不全是  你这样搞得我们很苦恼
Not really. You've got everyone throwing a shit fit.
他们家承受的精神压力极大
Stress levels in that household would've been through the roof.
网络舆论风向就像天气瞬息万变
That Internet stuff drifts off like weather.
那不是真的憎恨  他们不过是随口一说  但夫妻之间的恨意 是很现实的
It's half hate. They don't mean it. The hate in a marriage, that's in 3D.
那是一种发自肺腑 刻骨铭心的恨
That's had work put into it. That's sincere.
- 对  我离过婚 - 呃
- Yeah. I'm divorced. - Um...
丈夫醒了可以说话了  他的供述妙极了
Husband's up and talking. You're gonna love his alibi.
我听到乔在楼上的尖叫声
I heard Jo screaming from upstairs.
当我冲过去的时候 她在房间里跌跌撞撞地乱晃
And when I ran in, she was walking 'round the room, stumbling.
她紧紧地 紧紧地抱着头好像很痛苦的样子
She was clutching... She was clutching her head as if she was in pain.
然后突然 她就停下来了
And then for a moment, she stopped.
然后就好像癫痫发作似的 她就
And then it was like a seizure, she was...
开始打 抓自己
thrashing... clawing at her own skin.
然后她转向
And she turned...
她一头撞在了 书桌上 很用力
She smashed her head... onto the desk, hard.
然后她 一把把我推开
Then she... she pushed me over.
估计玻璃瓶就是那时被砸碎的
That must've been when the bottle smashed.
然后她捡起了玻璃碎片 开始往自己身上划
Then she picked it up, and she started cutting herself.
就这里  她一直在挖这块
Here. She was gouging.
我试图阻止她
I tried to stop her.
但她还是不停地伤害自己
But she did this.
然后她就割喉自尽了
Then she cut her throat.
我试图阻止她
I tried to stop her.
她用玻璃割断了自己的喉咙
She cut her own throat with the glass!
先自残再自杀 却没有明显理由
Mutilated and then killed herself for no apparent reason?
要我说 这可能性也太小了吧
I'd say the odds are against that.
他说 她像是癫痫发作一样
He said it was like she was having a seizure.
也许是那蛋糕有问题
Maybe there was something in the cake.
- 蛋糕 - 上面用糖霜写了“死婊子”
- The cake? - It had "fucking bitch" iced on it.
- 也许是里面有什么东西 - 类似下药吗
- Could've been something in it. - Like a drug?
- 我不知道 - 会让人自杀的药吗
- I don't know. - That makes people kill themselves?
他的话听起来挺令人信服的
He was sort of convincing.
- 他看起来并不 - 别说“像杀人犯”
- He just doesn't seem the... - Don't say "the type."
他很普通  普通人也有可能是杀人犯
He's ordinary. That is the type.
什么 所以是他把妻子的头狠狠撞向书桌的吗
What, so he bounced her head off the desk?
- 布鲁 - 把她抓得紧紧地 足以
- Blue. - Held her steady enough...
- 布鲁 - 什么
- Blue. - What?
- 蛋糕已经被送去药检了 - 好的
- Toxicology are looking at the cake. - Okay.
我们去调查下送蛋糕的人吧
Meantime, let's drop in on the person that sent it.
今早我查到名字了
Got the name this morning.
- 你不用这么故意迎合我 - 我们在依你行事啊
- You don't need to patronize me. - We're doing what you want.
- 跟进另一条线索 - 但你觉得这是浪费时间
- Following another lead. - That you think is a waste of time.
死胡同也得走一遍才能证明是真的走不通
Picking along dead ends just to prove they're dead ends,
干这行就是这样
that's most of the job.
我不是说这是浪费时间  只是
I'm not saying it's a waste of time. Just...
你还没有感受到现实的无趣呢
you haven't had a chance to get bored of reality yet.
好吧 我刚刚是有点傲慢了
Okay, that was patronizing.
- 这就是送蛋糕的人吗 - 对
- Is this who sent the cake? - Uh-huh.
- 你调查过她的社交账号吗 - 我不知道
- Have we checked her social feeds? - I don't know.
“去死吧乔·鲍尔特”  这是她周一早晨发的
"Death to Jo Powers." She posted that on Monday morning.
面包店说他们本不想做这种带脏话的蛋糕的
The bakery said that they're not meant to do obscenities,
我告诉他们 这是给我姐姐的 开玩笑而已
so I said it was for my sister, like just a joke thing,
他们就同意了
and they agreed, so...
不便宜啊 他们的蛋糕  算上运费 大概是80英镑吧
Not cheap, their cakes. With delivery, it was what, 80 quid?
嗯 钱也不是我一个人付的
Um... Well, I didn't pay for it all myself.
- 我们每个人付了一英镑 - 我们
- We all put a pound in each. - We?
嗯  我在一个妈妈和保姆的论坛里
Yeah. I'm on a mums and carers message board.
发起了集资
I held a sort of whip-round.
- 所以这钱是众筹的 - 嗯 如果你想这么说的话
- You crowd-sourced the money? - Yeah, if you like.
从其他80人那里吗
From 80 other people?
听着 我没
Look, I'm not...
我没在开玩笑 好吗  我知道她已经死了
I'm not being funny, okay? I know she is dead.
但你读过她写的东西吗
But did you read what she had written?
你觉得她写的那坨屁话 为她赚了多少钱
How much do you think she got paid for spouting that horrible shit?
我不知道
I don't know.
- 这是我的言论自由权 - 用来恐吓他人
- I was just using my freedom of speech. - To send a threatening message.
只是好玩 好吗
It was funny, okay?
我知道如果这蛋糕是我一个人买的话 就有点奇怪了
And I can see if I'd done it myself, then that would be a bit weird,
但我没疯
but I'm not mental.
你曾希望她去死
You wished she was dead.
嗯 呃
Well, uh...
不不 我没有
No, no, I didn't.
- “去死吧乔·鲍尔特” - 那只是
- "Death to Jo Powers." - That's just...
那只是带话题炒热度而已  写上“去死吧”
It's a... a hashtag game, you know, like "Death to..."
后面加上某个混蛋的名字
You insert the name of someone who's being an arsehole.
这不是 真的  只是开个玩笑
It's not... real. It's a joke thing.
谁发起的呢  那个话题
And who started it? The hashtag?
我不知道  我不知道  我只是正好看见了
I don't know. I don't know. I saw it somewhere.
不好意思失陪一下
Excuse us a moment.
药检结果出来了 蛋糕没问题
Toxicology say the cake's clean.
他们还说 “谢谢了 蛮好吃的”
They also said:"Thanks, it was delicious."
我们给她个警告吧  涉嫌违反电讯法
We'll give her a caution. Offensive Communications Act.
- 蛋糕的事就这么过去了吗 - 至少对她而言 是这样的
- Does that cover cakes? - As far as she's concerned, it does.
那参与众筹的其他人呢  你也要去警告他们吗
What about the others who chipped in? Are you going to tell them off, too?
- 我什么都没做 - 是你开的头
- I didn't do anything. - Start a thread about it.
丈夫明天就能出院
Hospital's discharging the husband tomorrow.
我们会传讯审问他
We'll bring him in for questioning.
布鲁  我们会逮捕丈夫  别再对这事耿耿于怀了
Blue? We're arresting the husband. Don't wallow in that.
互联网上今天又会转移话题了
The Internet will be pissed off with someone else today.
图斯克
Tusk.
他现在成了众矢之的 因为骂那小孩的事
Everyone's pissed off with Tusk 'cause of that thing with the kid.
他这事可是席卷各大社交网络啊
He's catching a shit storm on social media.
- 丽莎又会组织大家买蛋糕了 - 是啊
- Liza will be organising the cake now. - Yeah.
- 明天见 - 明天见
- See you tomorrow. - See you.
(滚回家吧图斯克  图斯克死期到了)
(垃圾 恶心  那个小孩真是太可爱了  图斯克说唱)
漂亮小姐姐在哪呢
Where my ladies at?
- 哟  演出不错啊 - 那不是 好极了 兄弟
- Yo! Good show. - Yeah, that's a good show, brother.
- 好的要上天了 - 想来一口吗
- I'm feeling my shit. - You want some of that?
- 你抽什么呢 - 好东西 朋友
- What you smoking? - Good shit, boy.
好啊
A'ight.
妈啊
Damn!
监控 监控 监控
Eyes on, eyes on, eyes on.
别紧张  这儿合法
Don't stress. It's legal here.
呸  记性不好  欧洲欢迎你啊
Pfft! Keep forgetting. Welcome to Europe, I guess.
- 搞得我没劲了 - 可不是么
- Kinda takes the joy out of it. - Tell me about it.
小心点  你搞坏了要赔的
Careful! You break it, you pay for it.
总是瞎搞
Always doing some bullshit.
图斯克  图斯克
Tusk? Tusk?
哟哟  谁来帮帮忙
Yo, yo! We need some help over here!
- 我在这呢 - 把它搞出来  把它搞出来  把它搞出来
- I got you. - Get it out! Get it out! Get it out!
叫救护车
Call an ambulance!
开始
Commencing.
- 他说是什么事了吗 - 没
- Did he say what it is? - Nope.
(第三天)
- 早上好 - 早上好
- Good morning. - Morning.
尸体在这里面
She's in here.
我顺着伤口深入后发现
So I go in,
这可不止是玻璃划出的伤口
and there's not just the wound from the glass.
那里有个洞  凹槽  一个钻孔 就像一个小隧道一样
There's a hole. Dug in. A bore hole, like a tiny tunnel.
我顺着深入 你知道有多深吗
So I follow it, you know, how deep does it go?
从耳道直深入大脑
It goes all the way from her ear canal to deep in her brain.
这个是在她脑内发现的
Where I find this.
就停在大脑内  看起来还蛮舒适的
Nestled right in there. Looks quite cosy.
- 是那种像蜜蜂似的机器人 - 人工智能蜂
- It's one of those bee things. - An ADI.
颗粒企划公司制造的自控昆虫机器人
An Autonomous Drone Insect from the Granular Project.
- 它是怎么进去的呢 - 我想是自己凿洞进去的
- How did it get in there? - I'd say it burrowed in.
- 卧槽 - 这还不是最可怕的
- Fuck me. - That's not the worst part.
它在后脑岛里钻了个洞
It crawled right through her dorsal posterior insula,
那是大脑掌控痛觉的区域
which is basically the brain's pain centre.
这种疼痛是常人无法承受的
You're talking agony off the scale.
- 为了停止疼痛你会不惜一切代价 - 即使是割喉自刎
- You'd do anything to make it stop. - Even cut your own throat.
- 下午好 - 我是帕克探员
- Good afternoon. - DCI Parke.
- 我是实习探员布鲁·科尔森 - 好的  谢谢
- TDC Blue Colson. - Okay. Thank you.
这些公司看起来真是光鲜得不得了啊
They're so fucking fancy-looking, these companies.
- 砸了几亿镑树立品牌 - 好吧 他们有钱
- Billions on branding. - Well, they can afford it.
整个人工智能蜂项目都是有政府资助的
The whole ADI project's pretty much bankrolled by the government.
所以弄得人心惶惶的
It's why so many people are paranoid about it.
我猜猜 你是说的某些网友吧
Let me guess, this is some people on the Internet?
他们认为政府用这些蜜蜂来监视我们
They reckon the government uses the bees to spy on us.
病态的世界观啊
There's a schizophrenic world view.
天哪 我可从来没想过能活在未来世界
Jesus, I didn't expect to find myself living in the future,
但我现在竟然就穿越来了
but here I fucking well am.
- 你是卡琳·帕克吗 - 是
- Karin Parke? - Uh-huh.
我是瓦内萨·达尔
Vanessa Dahl.
请跟我来
Please. Follow me.
你们来是想询问我们的人工智能蜂项目的吧
You're after information on our Project Swarm ADIs?
没错
That's right.
有什么特殊原因吗
Any particular reason?
对
Yes.
拉斯马斯
Rasmus.
拉斯马斯·斯乔伯格
Rasmus Sjoberg.
- 他是这个项目的领头人 - 很高兴认识你们
- He heads Swarm. - Nice to meet you.
- 嘿 - 嗨
- Hi. - Hi.
- 温室不错 - 对啊
- Nice greenhouse. - Yeah.
嗯 你的蜜蜂 你的人工智能蜂 可以给我介绍一下吗
So, your bees, your ADIs,talk me through them.
蜂群崩溃失调症 我们还不知道原因
Colony Collapse Disorder. We still don't know what's behind it.
蜜蜂已经差不多灭绝了
Bees themselves were virtually extinct
我们的人工智能蜂就起到了代替它们的功能
so what our ADIs do is effectively stand in for them.
它们是太阳能的  他们不需要采蜜
They're solar powered. They don't need nectar.
但它们一样可以传播花粉
but they pollinate flowers the same way.
它们爬进花中 花粉就会黏在它们腿上
They crawl inside, pollen sticks to their legs
它们再飞到下一朵花上抖落花粉
and gets brushed off the next flower they visit.
- 他们可以生产蜂蜜么 - 呃 不行
- Can they make honey? - Uh... No.
只是开个玩笑
I was joking.
它们怎么知道花在哪
How do they know where the flowers even are? I mean...
嗯 它们有传感器
Well, they have a sensor.
像摄像头一样吗
Like a... camera?
不是  只是基础的视觉传感器
No. Just a basic visual sensor.
它们需要基本的图像识别功能
You see, they need rudimentary pattern recognition
这样才能定位可兼容的植物群并导航
in order to locate compatible flora and navigate.
- 它们可以导航吗 - 可以
- They navigate? - Yes.
你不 我不懂 操控它们吗
You don't... I don't know... steer them?
它们是自动的  对吧
They're autonomous. That's right, isn't it?
它们自己决定该干什么  它们自己照顾自己
They make their own decisions. They look after themselves.
对  人工智能蜂遍布全英
Yes. You see, the ADIs cover the whole of the UK.
我们没有办法分别控制每一只
We couldn't command each one individually ourselves.
逻辑上来说这不可能
It's just not logistically possible.
不  我们只是设定行为模式 让它们自己运作
No. We simply set the behaviour and leave them to it.
它们甚至可以自己建蜂巢
hey even construct these hives themselves.
它们会自我繁殖
They reproduce...
- 它们自我繁殖 - 是的  每一个蜂巢都有复制点
- They reproduce? - Yes. Each hive is a replication point.
- 有点像3D打印机 - 是的
- It's like a 3D printer, basically. - Exactly.
它们自己生产自己的复制品
They create duplicates of themselves,
建造更多的蜂巢 以指数级速度扩散
create more hives and spread out exponentially.
- 覆盖全国 - 也许你应该来这儿工作
- Cover the country. - Maybe you should work here.
我读过这方面的文章  真了不起
Yeah, well, I read up on it. It's impressive.
是啊  存在这样的必要性也是蛮让人羞愧的
It is. It's just a shame it's necessary.
不然会产生环境灾难
The alternative would have been environmental catastrophe.
蜜蜂正在灭绝
Bees were dying out.
所以 什么风把你们吹到这儿来了
So, what is it that brings you here?
我们认为你的一只人工智能蜂和一起不明死亡有关
We think one of your ADIs may be involved in an unexplained death.
不好意思  死亡
Sorry? A death?
嗯
Uh-huh.
谢谢
Thank you.
是的  这是我们的  可是 他们不是被设计来
Yeah. It's one of ours. But, look, these are not designed to...
杀人吗  我也希望不是  是不是发生了什么故障呢
Kill people? I'd hope not. Could it have malfunctioned somehow?
不会的  当它们发生故障的时候
No. I mean, when they do malfunction...
这有时候会发生 但是它们会直接坏掉 掉在地上
It happens, but then they just break, they just hit the ground.
有没可能是有人黑进了一只自控昆虫机器人 并找到了控制的方法
What if someone hacked one and then they found a way of controlling it?
那是不可能的
That's impossible.
它的加密技术是军用级别的
You see, it's got military-grade encryption,
你还需要诊断控制器 那个也是加密的
and you would need a diagnostic controller, which is also encrypted.
所以我认为这种可能性是
So I would say the likelihood is...
我听不懂他在说什么 但听起来也不是完全不可能的
I don't know what he's saying, but it's not the same as "impossible."
这是我们线上的每一个蜂巢
This is every hive we have online.
看吧
See...
这些是这栋楼里的蜂巢
These are the hives in the building here.
- 一个蜂巢里有多少只蜜蜂 - 大约4000只
- How many bees per hive? - Around 4,000.
- 看起来有点像交通管制 - 是的
- It's like air traffic control. - Yeah.
那是搜索框吗
Is that the search input?
- 是的 但是 呃 你需要 - 不好意思
- Yeah, but, uh... you'd need... - Sorry.
乔·鲍尔斯的邮编
Jo Powers' postcode.
这是为了她的事吗
Is that who this is about?
- 你刚说有一些会出故障 - 很少的一部分 是的
- You said you get some malfunctions? - A fair few, yes.
它们可能会撞到车上  有一些会被人们抓住
They smack into a car or something. We even had people trap them.
把它们放进微波炉里拍YouTube视频
You know, put them in the microwave for YouTube videos.
而这个系统会记录所有的故障情况吗
And this logs any that drop off the system?
什么都记录 是的
Logs everything, yes.
周一晚上这附近有没有蜜蜂掉线呢
Did you lose any around here on Monday evening?
嗯 我查查看
Well, I can check.
只有一只  在19:03左右掉线  我可以回放
Just one. Went out at 1903 hours. Here, I can replay.
这儿
There.
- 这就奇怪了 - 什么奇怪
- That's odd. - What's odd?
当它们在蜂巢之间移动时
When they pass between hives,
它们的管辖权也会在蜂巢之间交换
they switch from one jurisdiction to another.
- 这有点像 - 有点像信号发射塔之间的电话信号吗
- It's, you know, like a...- It's like a phone between cell masts?
正解  它想这么做 但没有蜂巢愿意接收它
Exactly. It tried to do that, but there was nothing to switch to.
除非有人伪造了一个蜂巢并用此控制你的蜜蜂
Unless someone spoofed a hive and then they've used that to commandeer your ADI.
不行 你还需要一个诊断控制器才能做到
No, you would need a diagnostic controller to do that.
控制器的使用范围是多大
What's the range on one of those?
10到20米 大概
Ten, 20 metres, perhaps.
所以不管是谁在控制这个 他一定要在20米范围之内
So whoever was controlling it would have to be no more than 20 metres away.
- 就在房子外面 - 是的  甚至就在一辆车里
- Outside the house. - Yeah. Sitting in a car, even.
- 你可以追踪到是谁干的吗 - 是的  我已经开始查了
- Can you trace back who did this? - Yes. I-I'm already trying to do that.
你知道吗  我一个人可能会追踪得更快
You know what? Uh...It would be easier without an audience.
好吧
Okay.
你们两个交换一下号码 保持联系
You two swap numbers, keep a line of communication.
如果需要的话 你可以关闭整个系统吗
Can you shut the whole thing down if need be... hypothetically speaking?
哪怕是短暂的停止 都会对整个生态系统造成破坏
Even a short stoppage would damage the ecosystem,
而且我们还需要环保部的同意
and we'd need approval from the Department of the Environment.
我们需要有系统权限的所有颗粒企划公司的员工名单
We'll need a list of any Granular staff that had access to that system,
在职的和离职的都要
past or present.
有一些是政府雇员
Some were government employees.
如果有帮助的话 用不同的字体把他们标出来
Use a different font for those if it helps.
再见
Bye.
尼克 这是颗粒企划公司的人事记录
Nick, that's a set of Granular personnel records.
找出任何有嫌疑的人
Root out anyone interesting.
可能不止一个  有可能是团伙犯案
Maybe not just one. Could be a group involved.
其实我们应该上报给国家犯罪局
Technically we should refer this up to the NCA,
但他们休想从我这里抢走这个案子
but there's no fucking way they're taking this off me.
国家犯罪局已经知道了
The NCA already knows about it.
什么
What?
你是卡琳·帕克探员吗
DCI Karin Parke?
- 是的 - 我是肖恩·李  国家犯罪局的
- Yes. - Shaun Li, National Crime Agency.
什么风把你吹过来了
How come you're here?
这种情况不止一例
There's been more than one.
这是图克斯 昨晚的事
This is Tusk, last night.
- 见鬼 - 他们以为他只是突发痉挛
- Shit. - They thought it was a fit.
把他送去了医院
Took him to the hospital.
为了防止他伤害自己 他们给他打了麻醉
He had to be anaesthetised to stop him mutilating himself.
X光显示他的脑部有一处淤血或者肿瘤之类的东西
X-ray seemed to indicate some kind of plaque or tumour in his brain
他们就给他做了核磁共振
so they popped him in the MRI.
对啊  其实就是一个大磁铁
Yeah. Basically one big magnet.
撕开他的眼窝 把这个直接吸了出来
Tore it right out of his head, through the eye socket.
也弄坏了这只人工智能蜂
Battered the ADI too.
你们的那只更完整 我需要拿去分析
Yours is more intact so I'm gonna need it for analysis.
这是证据
It's evidence.
两起命案就形成模式了  意味着不是由于系统故障
Two's a pattern. It knocks any malfunction theory in the head.
- 而且受害者的情况都相似 - 相似
- And they're similar victims. - Similar?
两人都是网络讨伐的对象
Both in the middle of online shit storms.
如果你想除掉一个人 不是有无数种更简单的方法吗
Well, if you wanna kill someone, there's a million easier ways to do it.
用这个的话 你隔着一条街都能做到
Pull this off and you've done it from across the street.
不会留下指纹和DNA  就像把他们咒死了一样
No fingerprints, no DNA. It's like wishing them dead.
他妈的
Fuck.
该死
大伙  过来一下
Guys? Come here.
好 所以 乔·鲍尔斯和图斯克
Okay, so, um... Jo Powers and Tusk,
两人都被网民们谩骂了很久
both were being kicked around the Internet for hours,
但在这两个人的案子中 人们都把他们的照片和一个话题标签
but in both their cases, people were also tweeting their photos
“去死吧”一起转发
accompanied with this hashtag: #DeathTo.
(去死吧 图斯克)
- 就像那个老师一样 - 没错
- Like our friend the teacher. - Right.
她不知道最初是从哪里看到这个标签的 但是往前追溯的话
She didn't know where she'd first heard of it, but trace it back,
看起来第一次有人使用这个话题标签 是在上周末
and it looks like the first real use of the hashtag was last weekend.
- 是谁 - 呃
- By who? - Uh...
看起来像
Looks like, um...
看起来是一堆僵尸号发了一模一样的内容
Looks like identical tweets from a set of duplicate bot accounts.
呃
Um...
自动的  有点像垃圾邮件
Automated. It's like spam.
有人想推广这个标签 懂吗  就用这种办法来推广它
This is someone trying to seed the tag, you know? Get it out there.
像个诱饵  有人希望人们开始使用它
It's like bait. This is someone wanting people to pick up on it.
看看这个发送者的头像
Check out the senders' avatar photos.
蜜蜂  该死的
Bees. Shit.
好吧
Okay.
还不止这些
There's more.
每条推文都附带了一个说明视频
So each tweet had a sort of instruction video attached to it.
- 嗯嗯 - 这个
- Uh-huh. - There.
“报应游戏”
"Game of Consequences"?
有点像讨厌度竞赛
It's like an unpopularity contest.
选一个你不喜欢的人 如果足够多的人选择同一个名字
Pick someone you don't like and if enough other people choose the same name,
这个人就会成为目标
then that's who gets targeted.
这个 看
Here, watch.
报应游戏
Game of Consequences.
- 一 选择一个目标 - 噢 上帝啊
- One: Pick a target. - Oh, my God.
二 发送他们的照片和名字 并带上“去死吧”的标签
Two: Post their name and photo with #DeathTo.
不
No.
三 每天被提到最多的人 会在下午5点后被清除
Three: Most popular target will be eliminated after 5 p.m. each day.
四 游戏会在午夜重新计数
Four: Game resets at midnight.
- 哦 不 - 操
- Oh, no. - Fuck.
有人在进行一个公开投票 来杀掉票数最多的人
Someone's holding a public ballot, bumping off the top person.
- 天呐 太疯狂了 - 是的 而且参与的人越来越多
- Jesus, it's just mad. - Yeah, and it's growing.
第一天  63个人对乔·鲍尔斯使用了那个话题标签 对吧
Day one. 63 people used the hashtag on Jo Powers, okay?
第二天 223个人对图斯克使用了那个标签
On day two, 223 used it on Tusk.
- 现在谁在用 - 现在 现在人更多了
- Who's using it now? - There's... There's loads more people.
有不少人对财政大臣在用那个话题
There's quite a few votes for the Chancellor.
- 是啊 - 嗯
- Yeah. - Um...
但排第一位的是
But at number one...
有880人将标签用在了克莱拉·米德斯的身上
is 880 people using it on someone called Clara Meades.
- 她是谁 - 克莱拉·米德斯
- Who's she? - Clara Meades.
好吧 她好像在演示什么
Okay, um... it looks like she was at a demo,
她在一座战争纪念碑前自拍
and she took a selfie in front of a war memorial.
- 假装要向上面撒尿 - 干得漂亮 克莱拉
- Pretending to piss on it.  - Nice work, Clara.
嗯 离投票结束越来越近了
Yeah, it's getting near the end of the vote,
提到她的也越来越多
and her mentions are blowing up.
- 图斯克的事公众还不知道吗 - 呃 不知道
- Tusk isn't public knowledge yet? - Um, no.
所以大家并不知道这个标签的作用  他们就是想吓唬她
So people can't know the hashtag works. They're using it to scare her.
- 嗯 但他们会害死她 - 我们需要在五点前找到她
- Yeah, but they're gonna get her killed. - We need to get to her before five.
好  查看她的市民信息
Yeah. Pulling her citizens details.
你没有权限查看那些信息
You're not supposed to have access to that.
是 我知道  我只是为了找到她
Yeah, I know. Just getting her location.
在这儿
There.
(讨厌你 你应该被吊死)
(人渣中的人渣)
(去死吧克莱拉·米德斯)
(克莱拉·米德斯 什么鬼？！)
(他们为你的自由而战死)
(你妈的)
喂
Hello?
嗯 她在  好的 好的 稍等
Yeah, she is. All right, all right, hold on.
克莱拉
Clara!
警察  找你的  他们怎么知道我电话的
Police. For you. How did they get my number?
- 喂 - 克莱拉·米德斯吗
- Hello? - Clara Meades?
我是伦敦警察厅的探员卡琳·帕克
This is DCI Karin Parke, Met Police.
很抱歉这样找到你 但我们认为你可能有危险
Sorry to track you down like this, but we think you may be in danger.
抱歉 这是玩笑吗  因为目前我收到的这些东西都不好玩
Sorry, is this a joke? Because all this stuff I'm getting is not funny.
我没开玩笑  在我们来之前哪儿也别去
I'm not joking. Stay where you are until we get there.
关上窗户
And keep your windows closed.
我已经派人拉起了警戒线
I'm setting up a perimeter.
打给拉斯马斯 我们需要他帮忙
Call Rasmus, we need him across this.
- 拉斯马斯吗 - 你好 布鲁
- Rasmus? - Hi, Blue.
我给你发一个邮编 还有我的GPS定位
I'm sending you a postcode and my GPS.
你来监视这个地区
I need you to monitor the area.
持续跟踪我的位置 看看有没有异常 有没有下线的人工智能蜂 好吗
Track my location and see if you get anything unusual, any rogue ADIs, yeah?
嗯 好 好的
Yeah, great, good.
听着 如果他们又犯案了
Look, if they come back,
我觉得我能抓住他们
I think I can catch them.
我设置了一个陷阱
I have basically set a trap.
如果他们 如果他们再次犯案 我们能抓到他们
So if they... if they try it again, we've got them.
- 你是蝙蝠侠吗 - 这是新推出的
- Are you Batman? - They only just rolled them out.
这个可以把从这儿到那儿的所有红灯变成绿灯
This'll turn every red light between here and there to green.
我靠  如果这就是国家犯罪局的日常 我真该申请调岗
Fuck me. If this is the NCA life, I should apply for a transfer.
走吧
Let's go.
我们可以带她到这儿
We can take her here.
通常情况下 这房子是给恐怖活动的线人准备的
It's a safe house for terrorist informers usually.
没有发现目标
No target sighted.
这是警方行动
This is a police operation!
所有人 请立即离开屋内
Everybody vacate their premises now.
请离开
Please leave...
- 怎么回事 - 有人想黑进来
- What's that? - Someone's trying to break in.
- 拉斯马斯 - 我刚找到一个恶意攻击入口
- Rasmus? - I just picked up an attempted breach.
是颗粒企划公司 他们找到一个恶意攻击入口
Granular, they've got a breach.
- 一只人工智能蜂刚刚下线了  - 在哪儿
- One ADI just went offline. - Where?
- 距离你800米 - 在我们的封锁线外
- 800 metres from your location. - That's outside our cordon.
如果有人遥控蜜蜂向这边飞行
If someone's trying to pilot it this way,
他们看到这些穿警服的 也会立即掉头
they're gonna turn 'round the moment they see all these uniforms.
克莱拉·米德斯吧  我是卡琳·帕克  你收拾好行李了吗
Clara Meades? I'm Karin Parke. Did you pack a bag?
- 嗯 都放在门边了 - 好 走吧
- Yeah, it's by the door. - Right, let's go.
- 拉斯马斯找到他们了吗 - 还没
- Rasmus got a track on them? - Not yet.
(追踪中)
只是以防万一 过了今晚就好了
It's just precautionary, and it's only for one night.
我去向局里汇报
Just gotta call in.
嗨
Hi.
没 还没有
No, not yet.
可能永远不会  颗粒企划正在找呢
Hopefully never. Granular are onto it.
明白
Understood.
肖恩说 他们曾让一个目击者在这儿住了一阵
They housed a witness here for a while, Shaun said.
- 肯定有孩子 - 你们有孩子吗
- Must've had kids. - Have you got kids?
没有
No.
没这计划
No plans.
上楼吧
Up the stairs.
- 拉斯马斯 - 没有  还是没找到
- Rasmus. - Still nothing. I can't trace it.
至少这是间套房
At least there's an en-suite.
- 什么也没有吗 - 没有
- Is there nothing? - No.
无论是谁 他们把自己隐藏得很好
Whoever it is, they've masked their path well.
但那不是
But that's not...
- 擦 - 怎么了
- Fuck. - What?
- 一整个蜂巢都下线了 - 什么意思
- We just lost a whole hive. - What does that mean?
满载人工智能蜂的蜂巢
Packed full of ADIs.
也全部下线了
Lost them all too.
- 不 拉斯马斯 - 上千只蜜蜂
- No... Rasmus? - There's thousands of them.
- 在哪儿 - 离你很近
- Where? - It's close to your location.
拉斯马斯 再说一次
Rasmus, say that again.
布鲁  布鲁  它离 它离你很近
Blue? Blue. It's close... It's very close to you.
发信息  发信息给我  拉斯马斯  发信息给 靠
Text it. Text it to me. Rasmus. Text it to... Shit.
我需要再装修一次吗
Do I get to redecorate?
喂  喂
Hello. Hello.
不
No...
他们掌控了整个系统
They've got the whole thing.
我们什么也做不了
We're not in control anymore.
- 他们掌控了整个系统 - 你在干什么
- They've got the whole thing. - What are you doing?
- 快修啊  你不能修好吗  - 闭嘴
- Fix it! Can't you fix it? - Shut up!
(拉斯马斯·斯乔伯格  快跑)
擦
Shit.
我们得走了  现在  现在  快
We need to go. Now. Now! Come on!
走  走 走 走
Go. Go, go, go.
怎么 怎么回事
What's... what's happening?
卡琳
Karin...
去里面  快
In there! Go!
- 帮我把门缝堵住 - 告诉我怎么了
- Help me block the gap! - Tell me what's going on!
你们快把我吓屎了
You're scaring the shit out of me!
哦  卧槽
Oh! Fuck!
风扇  风扇
The fan! The fan!
快把它赶走
Get it away from me!
慢慢来
Take your time.
我之前见过很多尸体
I'd seen so many bodies before.
在犯罪现场 解剖室里
At crime scenes, in autopsies.
但从没看过别人死在我的面前
But I'd never seen anyone die.
她就在那里
And she was right there.
你能描述一下你同事 科尔森小姐的反应吗
And can you describe the reaction of your colleague, Miss Colson?
布鲁受到了很大打击
Blue took it hard.
我会把它关掉
I'll shut it down.
我们之前认为这是一个人 附近的某个神秘先生
We thought this was one guy, some Mr. Mystery in the vicinity,
黑了一只人工智能蜂 并且亲自控制它
hijacking one ADI and personally controlling it.
但是这次有上千只
But there were thousands of them.
- 所以推论不成立 对吗 - 是的
- So it can't be that, right? - No.
- 一个人不可能一次操作上千只 - 不能
- One person can't fly hundreds at once. - No.
无论是谁 他们肯定是控制了整个系统
Whoever this is, they're controlling the whole system.
- 知道它在哪儿吗 - 哪儿都可能
- Do you know where from? - Could be anywhere.
你他妈得给我找出来
You need to fucking sort this out!
人工智能蜂怎么知道谁是目标
How do the ADIs know who to target?
它们可能跟你一样 用身份数据库找到了克莱拉
Could've found Clara the same way you did, the identity database?
不  那样只能找到大致的范围
No. That just gives you the basic area.
我们当时共处一室  但是它们只攻击她一个
We were in the room too, and they only went for her.
人脸识别  肯定是人脸识别
Facial recognition. It's got to be facial recognition.
也就是说他们的视觉感应器 也被黑了
Which means the feed from their visual sensors, that's been accessed too.
- 不可能 - 这是唯一的解释
- That's not possible. - It's the only explanation.
实际上 每只蜜蜂和蜂巢的视觉数据流都受到了额外的保护
Now look, the visual feed is secure between each ADI and the hive.
- 你说 - 虽然
- There you go. - Although...
因为政府支持这个项目的要求之一
one of the government's conditions for backing the project...
好了  够了
Okay. Enough.
我们不得不同意政府提供的安全服务
We had to consent to permitting government security services
让其可以控制我们的视觉数据流 正如条款中所说“保护国家安全”
access to the visual feed at times of quote, "increased national security."
我觉得这太过分了
Which is, as I understand it, pretty much all the time.
- 我当时很不愿意接受 - 但你还是同意了
- I wasn't happy about it. - Your lot went along with it.
这意味着你的生命中能有更多的选择
That implies a greater range of options than your lot presented.
- 所以政府的确监视我们 - 这些都是保密的
- So they are spying on us. - This is all classified.
那你做了什么 你是不是开了个后门 黑进了国家通信总部
So what did you do, did you put in a back door and route it through GCHQ?
你是管理闭路电视 和公路监控摄像头的
I mean, you do CCTV, you do traffic cams.
还有什么东西是你没有染指的
So what don't you have your fucking noses in?
成千上万的智能蜂到处飞 就是为了支撑生态系统吗
Look, millions of those things flying around, propping up the ecosystem?
好 真棒 拯救地球 哈利路亚
Well, that's great, save the planet, hallelujah!
政府不会往里投十几亿
Government's not going to pump billions into it...
就因为一些科学家这么说 顺便赚200张环保者的支持票
just 'cause some lab coat says so, and it grabs 200 green votes.
他们觉得有机会得到更多 他们就抓住了机会
They saw an opportunity to get more, they took it.
全国性的监控
Total nationwide surveillance.
我们用疑犯完全设想不到的方式 跟踪他们好几个星期
We tracked suspects for weeks in ways they couldn't dream of.
- 我们阻止了爆炸 枪击 - 通过监视大众
- We prevented bombings, mass shootings. - By spying on the public.
保护他们的平安 这正是他们想要的
And keeping them safe, which is what they want.
但克莱拉·米德斯并不安全 是吧 肖恩
Clara Meades isn't safe, though, is she, Shaun?
告诉我们你所知道的 可能会帮助我们
Knowing what you knew, that might've helped us,
但你却什么也没说 守住了你那些肮脏的小秘密
but no, you kept your little fucking secret.
好了  政府就是很婊  这大家早就知道了
Okay! The government's a cunt. We knew that already.
很快关于克莱拉的事就会传播开来
Word's going to get out about Clara.
大家会醒悟 然后让这个疯狂的暗杀游戏继续进行
The public's going to wake up and find this mental assassination game going on,
很快我们就会收到另一具尸体
and soon we're going to have another body.
- 我们应该怎么做 - 我不知道
- So what do we do? - I don't know.
我们完全被封锁了  瞎了一样
We're totally locked out. Totally blind.
如果我能发现他们是怎么入侵的
If I can work out how they got in,
我或许能进行反向工程 夺回控制权
I might be able to reverse engineer some means of getting control back.
人工智能蜂有命令日志吗 它们体内有缓存吗
Do the ADIs have a command log, on-board cache?
- 有 但加密了 - 我需要密码
- Yeah, but that's encrypted. - I'll need the key to that.
我调查了员工档案 找到了些犯罪嫌疑人
Been through the employee files, found some POIs.
带他们进来
Bring them in.
你要参与对颗粒企划员工的审讯吗
Are you sitting in on these? Granular interviews?
我还是去别处待着
I've got to be somewhere.
现在是7点15分
It's 7:15.
三件死亡案件与社交媒体上流行的话题标签有关
Three deaths have now been linked to a hashtag circulating on social media.
充满争议性的新闻评论员乔·鲍尔斯
Controversial journalist Jo Powers...
早上好  你发话题标签了吗
Good morning. Have you posted the hashtag?
这是真的 还是都市传说
Is it real or an urban myth?
上千人参入其中 他们是否也有罪
Well, thousands have been taking part, but how culpable are they?
每天都有人死亡 我们想听听你的想法
People are dying, and we want to hear your thoughts.
七号线 利亚娜
Line seven, Liana...
这是真的 这真的在发生
This is real, this is happening...
(去死吧  法林顿公爵)
她死了我很开心
I am happy to see her die.
并不是话题标签杀了他们  这只是个游戏
It's not the hashtag killing them. That's just a game.
如果你是个混蛋 那你活该被羞辱
Like, if you're an arsehole, you deserve to be shamed.
史蒂夫 五号线
Steve, line five.
但我想说的是 总有人排在第一位 不是吗
Yeah, but my point is, someone's gotta be top of the list, yeah?
所以为什么不让那些罪有应得的人排在第一位 比如种族主义者
So why not make it someone, you know, who deserves it, like a racist.
在这标签后 我看到过名人 政客 每个人
With the hashtag, I've seen celebrities, politicians, everyone.
这不代表你要鼓励人们参与其中
This doesn't mean you have to sit there encouraging people to take part.
问题是这件事已经发生了
The point is this is already happening.
而且群众都知道他们可以参与其中
And people know that they can jump onboard
因为没人知道他们做没做
because nobody will ever know if they did or didn't.
好了 先暂停争论 我们来看看前五名
Well, let's just pause for a moment and go back to that top five.
正如之前所说 第一名是首相
As we have been saying, the Chancellor is at number one,
我想让大家好好考虑一下
and I want us to think about that.
这正向我们反映了人民的选择
What does that tell us about the choice of the nation?
我看到他排第一 其实也没有很惊讶
Well, I can't say I'm surprised that he's number one on the list.
他已经有一段时间很不受欢迎了
He's been pretty unpopular for quite a long time now.
但是因此 他就应该排在第一名吗
But does that warrant his place on this list?
我是觉得 在这件事情上 人们不用想太多
I'm saying people don't have to think too hard about it.
现在他是第一名
Now that's he's number one,
这会形成更多讨论 可能还会有更多人投他的票
that should generate more discussions and probably more votes.
(配对ADI_HV20101252)
谢谢你抽时间来
Thanks for your time.
- 还是没找到吗 - 没有
- No good? - No good.
- 这真厉害 - 肖恩
- Well, that's all fascinating... - Shaun.
- 但我们打算什么时候关闭它 - 汤姆
- But when do we shut it down? - Tom.
原谅我怀疑你司的基本能力
Forgive me for being sceptical about your agency's basic competence.
- 汤姆 - 我现在他妈的是砧板上的肉
- Tom. - I'm on the fucking chopping block here.
名单上的第一名  人民的选择
Number one on the list. The people's fucking choice!
法林顿排在第四 他可是个恋童癖
Farrington's number four, and he's a paedophile.
- 他被怀疑是恋童癖 - 他就是  你知道的
- Suspected paedophile. - He did it. You know he did.
赶快关掉它  所有的社交媒体  整个网络 结束掉
Let's just shut it down. All social media. The whole bloody Internet, pull the plug.
就今天一天
Just for today,
至少等到拇指姑娘施展出才华
at least until Thumbelina here pulls his finger out
真的抓到人为止
and he actually catches someone.
我不建议关闭社交媒体
I wouldn't advise shutting things down.
- 但是我们可以  我们能做到不是吗 - 整个社交媒体吗
- But it's possible? We can do that? - The whole of social media?
- 对  弄得跟朝鲜一样 - 从技术上讲 是可以的
- Yeah. Pull a North Korea on it. - Well, yes, technically.
- 那就关掉 - 这不是个好主意
- Right, so push the off switch. - That's not a good idea.
- 不是吗 - 我觉得不是
- No? - Not in my opinion.
好吧 作为一个即将被攻击的对象 我请求把它关掉
Right, okay. It's just that speaking as a marked man, I beg to fucking differ.
如果我们关掉社交媒体 你还是排名第一
If we shut it down, you'll still be number one.
而且肯定会是第一名
Guaranteed to be, in fact.
他是对的  如果我们让它继续运行 起码还有几个小时时间
He's right. If we let it run on, at least there's a few hours.
在五点前 任何事都可能发生  投票结果可能会改变
Anything could happen before five o'clock. The vote might change.
对 但也有可能不会  报告怎么说  那份档案
Yeah, and it might not. What about that report? The archive job?
1985年 提到法林顿的那份备忘录
From 1985, that memo about Farrington?
- 但那与这件事毫不相关 - 泄露它
- That was over an unrelated matter. - Leak it.
汤姆 那就是诽谤了
Tom, that would be a smear.
我也希望是 那只是彻底的诽谤
A head-to-toe shit smear, I fucking hope so.
他已经80岁了  已经活够了  快让他去死
He's in his 80s. He's had his life. Fuck him under the bus.
我能提出一个替代方案吗  我们把你转移到一个安全的地方
If I could suggest an alternative? We move you to a safe location.
- 保证你五点前是安全的 - 昨天你不也这么做了 很有效啊
- Have you secured before five. - Worked out well for you last night.
我给你看
I'll show you.
下一个是泰丝·沃伦德  她是大三学生
This next one's Tess Wallender. She was a junior.
所以没有多少专业技能
So not much in the way of technical skills.
- 因个人原因退出颗粒企划 - 神经衰弱
- Quit Granular for personal reasons. - Nervous exhaustion, yeah.
之前在人力资源部门工作
Worked in Human Resources for Granular until she quit.
她拍了油管上一名男子的照片 说他骚扰她
She took a photo of a guy on the Tube, said he'd harassed her,
下流评论什么的
lewd comments or something.
结果他有学习障碍 所以她不断地侮辱他
Turned out he had a learning disability so she caught a ton of shit on...
在社交媒体上
On social media.
- 你好 我是卡琳·帕克探员 - 你好
- Hello. I'm DCI Karin Parke. - Hi.
就像整个天气系统都与我作对
It was like having a whole weather system turn against me.
一条接着一条的憎恨消息 日以继夜地不断涌进来
Just hate message after hate message, around the clock, all piling on.
很难讲清楚 他们对我的情感带来了什么影响
It's hard to describe what that does to your head.
突然间 无数你看不见的人
Suddenly there's a million invisible people,
全都在谈论他们多鄙视你
all talking about how they despise you.
这感觉像精神病
It's like a mental illness.
操
Fuck.
怎么了
What?
卧槽
Shit.
我的意思是 我认输了 我犯错了
I mean, hands up, I made a mistake,
但是人们喜欢对我穷追猛打这一点 让我很受打击
but the way people enjoyed kicking me, that's what got to me.
这对他们来说只是一时的乐趣
The casual fun they had and, um...
我觉得我不能继续活下去了
I just felt I couldn't go on.
谁救了你
Who found you?
呃 加勒特 我的室友
Um... Garrett, my flatmate.
他在我割腕的五分钟后 在浴室里发现了我
He found me in the bath five minutes after I'd slashed them.
这很疯狂
I mean, it's crazy.
我已经半昏迷了 他把我拖出浴缸
I'm half-conscious. He's dragging me out of the bath,
我让他滚 说 “我没穿衣服”
and I'm telling him to get out, saying, "I'm naked."
他在我手腕上绑了毛巾 让我保持清醒
He tied towels 'round my wrists, kept me conscious,
直到救护车来 他都在抚摸我的头发 和我说话
kept stroking my hair till the ambulance arrived, talking to me.
感觉怪怪的
Sort of weird.
我觉得他一直对我有感觉
I think he always had a thing for me.
我们在同一个地方工作 所以你懂的 尴尬
And we worked at the same place so, you know... awkward.
- 他也在颗粒企划公司工作吗 - 对  他是人工智能蜂项目的
- He worked at Granular? - Yeah. On the ADI thing.
- 他是个神童  特别聪明 - 你说他叫什么来着
- He was a real wunderkind. Ultra-smart. - What did you say his name was?
加勒特  加勒特·斯科尔斯
Garrett. Garrett Scholes.
加勒特·斯科尔斯  我们要找到加勒特的下落
Garrett Scholes. We need the whereabouts of a Garrett...
斯科尔斯  我们正要告诉你
Scholes. We were about to tell you.
这被藏在乔·宝维斯脑子里找到那只蜜蜂的缓存里
It was buried in the on-board memory of the Jo Powers' ADI.
- 是什么 - 一份声明  98页的声明
- What was? - A manifesto. A 98-page manifesto.
看看这个  还有一张该死的自拍
And check this out. There's fucking selfies in it.
可以开始了吗
So we're good to go?
好了 就是这个地方
Okay, that's the charge in place.
好  撤退
Okay. Pull back.
我们都已就位
We're all set here.
引爆
Detonate.
计划是 我们把你转移到一座地下碉堡
So, the plan is, we move you to an underground bunker,
炸毁方圆十公里内的每一个蜂巢
knock out every hive within a ten-mile radius.
然后呢 把我留在那吗  要多久
And, what, just leave me there? How long for?
这只是临时方案
It's a temporary measure.
你需要多久来解决所有蜂巢
How long till you take out all the hives?
有2万到3万个蜂巢  要耗费两年时间
There's 20,000, 30,000 of them. That would take two years.
两年 一天一个受害者
Two years, a victim a day.
更重要的是 对环境的影响
More to the point, the environmental impact would...
去你的
Fuck that.
卧槽
Shit!
- 怎么了 - 操
- What? - Fuck!
退后 退后
Stay back, stay back!
往后退
Get back!
走走走 快跑
Go, go, go! Get away!
我操 快跑
For fuck's sake, move!
你有备用计划吗
What's your Plan B?
(报应的利齿)
他在最初的员工名单上 但我们无视了他
He was on the original employee roster, but we discounted him.
他六个月前出国了
He left the country six months ago.
我们以为我们在找附近的人
We thought we were looking for someone nearby.
仔细调查他  找到所有能找到的线索
Run a full trace on him. Everything we can find.
有生产价值的疯子 这是最糟的一种人
Lunatic with production values, that's the worst kind.
“感谢科技革命
"Thanks to the technological revolution,
使我们有权利去愤怒去指责 可以不计后果地发泄愤怒”
we have the power to rage and accuse, spout bile without consequence.
只有当我们被迫认识到科技赋予我们的能力
Only by being forced to recognize the power technology grants us,
认识到个体所承载的责任
to acknowledge individual responsibility..."
全都是这种玩意吗
Is it all like this?
他把人们比作昆虫 说人们在实施残忍中得到快感
He likens the population to insects, says we revel in cruelty,
这是由人性的恶产生的致命弱点
that it's a weakness that should be bred out of us.
他近些天来所说的主题 都是要让人们承担自己的言行所带来的后果
Recurrent theme is he wants people to face the consequences of what they say and do.
- 强迫他们去承担 - 所以这一切都是道德训诫吗
- Wants to force that on them. - The whole thing's a moral lesson?
他想让我们发现这个真相 再传播出去
He wanted us to find this and spread it about.
去他妈的
Well, fuck him.
操
Fuck.
(去死吧 加勒特·斯科尔斯)
(发布)
妈的
Shit.
卡琳  卡琳  他露出破绽了
Karin. Karin. He's messed up.
他是自己写的这份文件 对不对
He's put this document together himself, right?
他本人的名字在元数据里
His author name's in the metadata.
但是他抹掉了所有其他信息
But he stripped out everything else,
所以我们就不知道他什么时候写的这本书 没错吧
so we don't know when he's written it, for example.
没错
Mm-hmm.
书中大部分的图片都是网上的剪贴画 除了这一张
Most of the photos are clipart off the Internet, except this one.
- 自拍 - 这就是他的漏洞
- The selfie. - That's where he's screwed up.
他用自己的手机拍了自拍 照片上就会有手机留下的地理标志
He's taken it with his phone, and the phone left a geotag on the image.
- 所以你就能知道他是在哪里拍的自拍 - 我能知道精确的位置
- So you know where he took this? - I know precisely where.
他在这里 颗粒企划的总部在这里
He's here and Granular HQ is there.
- 武装警察 待在原地 - 武装警察
- Armed police! Stay down! - Armed police!
武装警察  待在原地  武装警察  站出来
Armed police! Stay where you are! Armed police! Show yourselves!
快
Move!
去左边
Left.
- 没有发现 - 没有发现
- Clear! - Clear!
没有发现
Clear!
典型的有钱名人作风
Lifestyles of the rich and famous.
看这儿  熔炉
There. The forge.
好东西
Nice one.
我在证据科接触的一半物证都是有烧焦痕迹的
Half the drives I sifted in forensics had scorch marks on 'em.
- 你怎么看 - 看起来像是他的工具包
- What do you think? - Yeah. Looks like his toolkit.
- 你会用吗 - 这就像是开门的钥匙
- You can use it? - Pretty much the key to the door.
你能重新控制它们吗  发送停用指令
So you can get control back? Send the deactivation?
我拿到了他的源代码
Well, I've got his source code.
- 我应该能逼他现身 - 动作快点
- I should be able to bounce him out. - Be quick.
开门的钥匙
Key to the door?
这家伙可不像是那种会把这么重要的证据双手奉上的人
Our guy doesn't seem the type to leave keys lying around.
我进去了
Well, I'm in.
很好  解除系统
Okay. Deactivate her.
- 我需要修复权限 - 见鬼
- Yeah, I need to repair permissions. - Fucking hell.
奇怪了
That's weird.
怎么了
What's weird?
- 时间不多了 - 那个文件  之前不在这里
- Time's ticking. - That file. Wasn't there before.
- 这个 - 是的
- This file? - Yeah.
是什么
What is it?
- 布鲁  - 我觉得是移动设备识别码
- Blue? - I think they're IMEI numbers.
什么意思
What does that mean?
每台手机 每个设备都有一串特殊的号码 移动设备识别码
Every phone, every device has a unique number, an IMEI number.
每串号码都与一个特定的用户相关联
It tethers it to a unique user.
- 没错 - 我可以查一下 就是反向追踪
- Yeah. - But I can check, just... reverse lookup.
放松点
Take it easy.
这些人都是谁
Who are these people?
我不知道  这里有38万7千人呢
I don't know. There's 387,000 of them.
这是你们的蜜蜂收集来的资料吗
Are these IDs your spooks have been collecting?
- 不  你准备好了吗 - 是的 差不多了
- No! Are you ready yet? - Yeah, almost there.
等等  等等
Wait. Wait.
那个老师叫什么来着
What was the name of that teacher? Hate cake.
- 莉莎  莉莎·巴哈尔 - 莉莎·巴哈尔
- Liza. Liza Bahar. - Liza Bahar.
去他妈的
Fuck's sake.
这是一份使用过死亡标签的人的名单
This is a list of everyone who's used the hashtag.
什么
What?
所有参与过报应游戏的人
Everyone who took part in the Game of Consequences.
看样子他们是从国家通信总部搜集了这些人的身份信息
They've hoovered up their ID from GCHQ by the looks of it.
你设的后门给他提供了方便
That backdoor worked both ways, it seems.
- 看一下有没有我的名字 - 什么
- See if I'm on there. - What?
我之前发布了这个标签 加上斯科尔斯的照片
I posted the tag earlier with Scholes' face.
- 只是为了看看他会有什么反应 - 好 好 差不多了
- Just trying to get a reaction from him. - Yeah, yeah, almost there.
没错 有你的名字
Yeah, you're there.
差不多好了
Almost there.
他为什么要搜集参与过这个游戏的人 我是说
Why has he collected everyone who took part? I mean...
好了  我准备好了
Okay. I'm ready.
- 见鬼 - 快开始运行
- Shit. - Run it now.
不  你们想想看  他是在给我们下套
No. Think. He left us a trail.
- 拜托 - 那张带有位置的照片
- Oh, come on. - That photo with the whereabouts,
他根本不会犯这种错误  他知道我们会追踪他
it's too big a mistake for him. He knew we'd do this.
- 所以我们现在就关掉它 好吗 - 也许这会引发这个游戏的最后一步
- Now we're shutting it down, all right? - And maybe that'll trigger some endgame,
可能和这个名单有关
something to do with that list.
会不会这些人才是他的真正目标
What if those are his real targets?
这名单上的所有人  所有参与过这个游戏的人
The people on the list. Everyone who took part.
报应
Consequences.
那些仇恨人物都只是诱饵  玩家才是最终目标
The hate figures were the bait. The players are the target.
- 启动失效指令 - 再等等 好吗
- Run the deact command. - Now just wait a minute, okay?
- 马上启动 - 不
- Run it. - No!
没错
Yeah.
好的 没事了
Yeah, it worked.
不好意思 我必须得这么做
Sorry, but that needed doing.
- 不 不 不 不 不 - 什么
- No, no, no, no, no. - What?
不 不
No. No.
- 操 - 不
- Fuck! - No.
见鬼
Shit.
哦 不
Oh, no.
你们看
There's...
我们都很熟悉接下来的惨剧
We're all tragically familiar with the rest of the events of that week.
死亡人数数目之大
And we need no reminding of the sheer scale
亦无需多言
of the loss of life that followed.
是的  没错
No. No, we don't.
科尔森小姐后来怎么样了
And what became of Ms. Colson?
我认为她非常自责
I think she blamed herself.
是的 我知道
No. I know she did.
她觉得是她的追查导致了这一切
She felt she'd followed his breadcrumb trail and sprung the whole thing.
她辞职了
She left the force.
我已经很久没有她的消息了
I didn't hear from her.
我试着给她打电话 发邮件 但是都没有回音
Rang her, tried emailing, but no response.
那么
Then, um...
大约四个月之后 他们在一处海滩找到了
About four months later, they found her things.
她的个人物品
On a beach.
和一封遗书
With a note.
她自杀了
She killed herself?
是的 可以这么说
That's the base theory, yes.
帕克小姐 请你随时待命
Ms Parke, I would like to commend you
如有需要 我会传唤你上庭并提供证词
for sharing your testimony and your time.
谢谢
Thank you.
谢谢你
先生
Señor.
- 谢谢 - 谢谢
- Gracias. - Gracias.
(一条新消息)
(找到他了)
(删除)